Register to The Henry Gilbert Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Music, 1891-1927; Series I; 11.9' (20 boxes)
  - Orchestra, I.B
    - [Dance in Place Congo] Dance in Place Congo: (after George W. Cable)
      - [Dance in Place Congo] Dance in Place Congo: (after George W. Cable), 1 score ([105] p.); 35 cm. (Box 5, Folder 62-63)
        "Copyright, 1922..." - p. 1.
        Cover with label in Henry Gilbert's hand from old binding laid in.
        Photograph of pp. 28-29 of above score (20 x 25 cm.) laid in.
      - [Dance in Place Congo] Dance in Place Congo: (after George W. Cable), 57 parts; 34 cm. (Box 5, Folder 64-68, Box 6, Folder 69)
        "London: Novello & Co." - on covers.
      - [Dance in Place Congo] Dance in Place Congo: (after George W. Cable), 5 extra parts; 33 cm. (Box 6, Folder 70)
        Includes: Violin I, violin II, viola, and violoncello.
      - [Dance in Place Congo] Dance in Place Congo: (after George W. Cable), 1 score (113 p.); 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 71)
        Two copies.
      - [Dance in Place Congo] Dance in Place Congo: (after George W. Cable), Proof sheets for the above score; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 72)
        With additions in ink and pencil, some pasted on.
    - [Dance in Place Congo. Selections] Dance
      - [Dance in Place Congo. Selections] Dance, 1 score (23 p.); 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 73)
        "Interpolation between measures 396 and 397" - p. 1.
        Notes by Henry Gilbert and Mrs. Henry Gilbert on cover.
      - [Dance in Place Congo. Selections] Dance, 55 parts; 34 cm. (Box 6, Folder 74-75)
      - [Dance in Place Congo. Selections] Dance, 1 score (6 p.); 33 cm. (Box 6, Folder 76)
        Interpolation between measures 105 and 106.
      - [Dance in Place Congo. Selections] Dance, 98 parts; 4-24 cm. (Box 6, Folder 77-78, Box 7, Folder 79-80)
        Manuscript and holographs in ink and pencil.
    - [Segue], 3 parts; 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 81)
      Piccolo and 2 flute parts.
    - [Dance in Place Congo (Sketches)] Melodic particles
      - [Dance in Place Congo (Sketches)] Melodic particles, [2] p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 7, Folder 82)
        "Material and sketch for third section of Dance in Place Congo" - cover.
      - [Dance in Place Congo (Sketches)] Melodic particles, Loose sheets ([50] p. of music); 21-34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 83)
        Portion of cover with note laid in.
      - [Dance in Place Congo (Sketches)] Melodic particles, Loose sheets ([1] p. of music); 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 84)
      - [Dance in Place Congo (Sketches)] Melodic particles, Loose sheets ([15]p. of music); 46 cm. (Box 92, Folder 85)
    - [Dance in Place Congo. Scenario] (Box 7, Folder 86)
      See also: H. Keyboard. Dance...; arr.
      - Detailed scenario, 9, [1] sheets; 25-28 cm.
      - Detailed scenario, 4 sheets; 28 cm.
        Typescript and copy.
      - Scenario, 9 sheets; 26 cm.
      - Scenario, 6 sheets; 28 cm.
        Typescripts and copies of typescripts, some incomplete, with holograph markings in pencil and ink.
        Dated: 1921-25.
      - Scenario, 4 sheets; 20 cm.
      - Scenario, 1 sheet; 32 cm.
        Holograph notes in pencil on a bank statement.
      - Scenario, 4 [i.e., 3] sheets; 28 cm.
        Typescript.
    - [Dewey Schottische], 8 parts; 18-35 cm. (Box 7, Folder 87)
      Holographs signed, in ink.
      Includes parts for: flute, cornet (2), piano, violin I, violin II, viola, and cello.
    - [Episodes] Two episodes: for orchestra. - Boston: H.F. Gilbert, c1897.
      - [Episodes] Two episodes: for orchestra. - Boston: H.F. Gilbert, c1897., 1 score (12 p.); 26 cm. (Box 7, Folder 88)
        Contents: I. Legend - II. Negro episode.
      - [Episodes] Two episodes: for orchestra. - Boston: H.F. Gilbert, c1897., 85 parts; 35 cm. (Box 7, Folder 89-94)
        Holographs signed, and manuscript in ink.
        Sheet with note laid in first folder of parts.
    - [Episode. Legend (Sketches)] (Box 7, Folder 95)
      - [Episode. Legend (Sketches)], 1 score ([1] sheet); 28 x 34 cm.
      - [Episode. Legend (Sketches)], [3] p. of music; 35 cm.
    - [Episode. Negro episode (Sketches)] (Box 7, Folder 95)
      See also: H. Keyboard. Episodes. Negro episode; arr.
      - [Episode. Negro episode (Sketches)], 1 score (8 p.); 27 x 35 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink and pencil.
      - [Episode. Negro episode (Sketches)], Loose sheet ([2] p. of music); 26 x 27 cm.
      - [Episode. Negro episode (Sketches)], ca. 297 parts; 15-28 cm.
        Manuscript (copies).
    - [Gavotte], 1 score (12 p.); 27 x 34 cm. (Box 7, Folder 96)
    - [Genghis Kahn (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([4] p.) of music; 29-35 cm. (Box 7, Folder 97)
      For orchestra?
    - [Humoresque] Humoresque: on negro-minstrel tunes. - New York: H.W. Gray, c1913., 1 score (54 p.), bound; 32 cm. (Box 7, Folder 98)
      Three copies, all contain measure markings in red ink.
    - [Humoresque (Sketches)] American humoresque (Box 7, Folder 98)
      - [Humoresque (Sketches)] American humoresque, 1 score (2 p.); 35 cm.
        "Class I orchestral composition" - end.
        "Old Dan Tucker" - p. 1.
        Lacking p. 3 to end.
      - [Humoresque (Sketches)] American humoresque, [4] p. of music; 35 cm.
    - [Indian sketches] Indian sketches: dedicated in friendship to Dr. and Mrs. J. Heiman.
      - [Indian sketches] Indian sketches: dedicated in friendship to Dr. and Mrs. J. Heiman., 1 score (92 p.), bound; 36 cm. (Box 8, Folder 99)
        [1911].
        Portion of wrapping with notes laid in folder.
        Contents: I. Prelude - II. Invocation - III. Song of the wolf - IV. Camp dance - IV. Nocturne - VI. Snake dance.
      - [Indian sketches] Indian sketches: dedicated in friendship to Dr. and Mrs. J. Heiman., Photostat (negative) of the above score; 30 x 38 cm. (Box 8, Folder 100)
        Does not include all markings of the original score.
      - [Indian sketches] Indian sketches: dedicated in friendship to Dr. and Mrs. J. Heiman., 59 parts; 34 cm. (Box 8, Folder 101-103)
        Parts marked "OK" except for 2 extra percussion parts marked "special part for B.S.O."
    - [Indian sketches (Sketches)] Prelude
      See also: H. Keyboard. Indian sketches; arr.
      - [Indian sketches (Sketches)] Prelude, 7 p. of music; 33 cm. (Box 8, Folder 104)
        'Sketch for piano and orchestra work based on "Indian scenes."'
      - [Indian sketches (Sketches)] Prelude, Loose sheets ([11] p. of music); 27-36 cm. (Box 8, Folder 105)
      - [Indian sketches (Sketches)] Prelude, Loose sheets ([157] p. of music); 25-35, 27 x 34 cm. (Box 8, Folder 106)
    - [Island of the Fay] Island of the Fay: (after Edgar A. Poe)
      - [Island of the Fay] Island of the Fay: (after Edgar A. Poe), 1 score (61 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 107)
        "Looked over corrected and edited, ready for copyist. Sept. 1923" - p. 1.
        Printed excerpt from Poe's "Island of the Fay" pasted to front fly-leaf.
      - [Island of the Fay] Island of the Fay: (after Edgar A. Poe), Photostat (negative) of the above score ([35] sheets); 30 x 38 cm. (Box 9, Folder 108)
        Receipt laid in.
      - [Island of the Fay] Island of the Fay: (after Edgar A. Poe), 1 score ([62] p.); 34 cm. (Box 9, Folder 109)
      - [Island of the Fay] Island of the Fay: (after Edgar A. Poe), 55 parts; 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 110-112)
        Holographs signed, in-ink.
        "OK" in pencil on covers of parts.
      - [Island of the Fay] Island of the Fay: (after Edgar A. Poe), 2 parts; 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 113)
        Clarinets I-II, both marked "rejected."
      - [Island of the Fay] Island of the Fay: (after Edgar A. Poe), 2 parts; 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 114)
        Holographs, one signed, in ink.
        Oboe I-II.
    - [Island of the Fay (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([30] p. of music); 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 115)
      See also: H. Keyboard. Island of the Fay; arr.
    - Legend
      See: Episodes.
    - [Massapoog Schottische], [1] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 116)
      B-flat cornet part for piece for orchestra?
    - Negro episode
    - [Negro rhapsody] New York: H.W. Gray, c1915., 1 score (62 p.), bound; 33 cm. (Box 9, Folder 116)
      Typed letter signed from WQXR to Mrs. Henry Gilbert, 1949 Mar 21, was laid in.
      See also: III.C.2. CORRESPONDENCE. Between Mrs. Henry Gilbert and others. To Mrs. Henry Gilbert.
    - [Negro rhapsody. Selections] Apotheosis from "Negro rhapsody.", [3] p. of music; 36 cm. (Box 9, Folder 116)
      Timpani with orchestra reduction.
      Contains note.
    - [Nocturne]
      - [Nocturne], 1 score (31 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 117)
        "Looked over ready for copyist Jan 1 1927" - title page.
        Typescript poem by Walt Whitman pasted on title page.
      - [Nocturne], Photostat (negative) of the above score; 40 cm. (Box 92, Folder 118)
        Pasted to pages of an issue of the Musical Courier (Vol. xciii - No. 27).
        Inscription by Henry Gilbert on cover.
      - [Nocturne], 27 parts; 35 cm. (Box 9, Folder 119)
        Holographs signed (?) in ink.
        Woodwinds, brass, and percussion only.
        "OK" marked on covers.
      - [Nocturne], 38 parts; 33 cm. (Box 9; 10, Folder 120; 121)
        Manuscript (copies)
        String parts only.
    - [Nocturne (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([50] p. of music); 14-34 cm. (Box 10, Folder 122)
    - Orlamonde
      See: H. Keyboard. Orlamonde; arr.
    - [Salammbô's invocation; arr.], 1 part ([1] p. of music); 34 cm. (Box 10, Folder 123)
      Unidentified part to arr. for orchestra?
      Unidentified pencil sketch on back.
      See also: E. Songs. Salammbô's Invocation to Tänith.
    - Shout
      See: Negro rhapsody.
    - [Spiritual], 1 score (31 p.); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 123)
    - [Strife], 1 score (46 p.), bound; 34 cm. (Box 10, Folder 124)
      "8 min." and "Not read" written in pencil on p. 1.
      [1910-25]
    - [Strife (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([81] p.); 36 cm. (Box 10, Folder 125)
    - [Suite, orchestra] Suite: for chamber orchestra
      - [Suite, orchestra] Suite: for chamber orchestra, 1 score (89 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 126)
        Holograph signed (copy) with pencil markings.
        Program with note taped to front fly-leaf.
        Note on typescript list of parts sent to Howard Hanson pasted to back of last page.
        [1926-7].
        Contents: I. Prelude - II. Spiritual - III. Fantasy.
      - [Suite, orchestra] Suite: for chamber orchestra, 15 parts; 31-35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 127-l28)
        "OK" in pencil on covers.
        Bassoon part contains note by Nicolas Slonimsky (1928 Apr 27), and pencil markings by Henry Gilbert.
    - [Suite, orchestra. Prelude], 1 score (19 p.); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 129)
      Holograph signed, in pencil.
    - [Suite, orchestra (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([34] p. of music); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 130)
    - [Summer-day fantasie] (Box 10, Folder 131)
      - [Summer-day fantasie], 1 score (25 p.); 27 x 46 cm.
        '"The morning wind forever blows" - Thoreau.'
      - [Summer-day fantasie], 1 score (25 p.); 34 cm.
        Pages 16-19 are blank.
    - [Summer-day fantasie (Sketch)?], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 131)
      holograph in ink.
    - [Symphonic piece]
      - [Symphonic piece], 1 score (76 p.), bound; 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 132)
        Three sheets with notes, parts and picture of Henry Gilbert pasted to front cover and fly-leaf.
        [1925].
      - [Symphonic piece], 1 score (75 p.); 35 cm. (Box 10, Folder 133)
      - [Symphonic piece], 62 parts; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 134-136)
    - [Symphonic piece (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([36] p.); 36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 137)
      Includes sketch dated: 1924 Oct 1.
    - [Symphonies, no. 1, E-flat major (Sketches)] (Box 11, Folder 138)
      - [Symphonies, no. 1, E-flat major (Sketches)], 7 sheets of music; 33 cm.
        "Sketch of 2nd movement. Sym. 1 E-flat" - in pencil on p. 1.
      - [Symphonies, no. 1, E-flat major (Sketches)], [2], 7 p. of music; 33 cm.
        "Work sheets for sketch for 2nd movement Symphony in E-flat - A" note laid in.
    - [Symphonies (Sketch)], [2] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 139)
      Unidentified symphony.
    - Two episodes for orchestra
    - Unidentified piece (Sketch), 12 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Band, I.C
    - [Dance] Dance: Jazz band score (Whitman's band)
      - [Dance] Dance: Jazz band score (Whitman's band), 1 score (23 p.); 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 141)
        Loose sheets ([5]) containing notes laid in.
        Ca. 1924?
      - [Dance] Dance: Jazz band score (Whitman's band), 22 parts; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 142)
        Names of instrumentalists on covers.
  - Chamber and Instrumental, I.D
    - [Gavotte], 1 score ([4] p.); 27-35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 143)
      For string quartet.
      Dated: 1894 Apr 15.
      Sketch at end.
    - [Quartets, strings] String quartet
      - [Quartets, strings] String quartet, 1 score (61 [i.e., [31]] sheets), bound; 36 cm. (Box 11, Folder 144)
        Manuscript signed by Henry Gilbert (photostat).
      - [Quartets, strings] String quartet, 1 score (61 p. [i.e., [31]] sheets); 23 x 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 144)
        Manuscript signed by Henry Gilbert (photocopy-negative, reduced).
      - [Quartets, strings] String quartet, 5 parts; 35 cm. (Box 11, Folder 145)
        Includes portion of violin I part (manuscript in ink).
    - [Quartets, strings (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([95] p.); 13-36, 27 x 34 cm. (Box 11, Folder 146-147)
    - [Quartets, strings] Quartette (Box 12, Folder 148)
      - [Quartets, strings] Quartette, 1 score (6 p.); 27 x 34 cm.
      - [Quartets, strings] Quartette, 4 parts; 35 cm.
        Movement "I"?
    - [Scherzino], 1 score ([3] p.) - 2 parts; 36 cm. (Box 12, Folder 149)
      Holograph in pencil (score) and ink.
      For violin, cello, and piano.
    - [Scherzo], 1 score ([1] p.); 27 cm. (Box 12, Folder 149)
      With: "Slumber song."
    - [Serenade], 1 score (7 p.) - 5 parts; 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 150)
    - [Sonata fantastique (Sketch)], 1 score (9 [i.e., 8] p.); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 151)
    - [Tempo di rag] (Box 12, Folder 152)
      - [Tempo di rag], 1 short score ([4] p.); 34 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink with markings in pencil and red ink.
      - [Tempo di rag], 8 parts; 34 cm.
        Flute, oboe, clarinet, cornet, violin I-II, cello, and piano parts.
      - [Tempo di rag], 5 parts; 35 cm.
        Violin I-II, viola, cello, and oboe parts only.
    - [Trios, violin, violoncello, piano], 3 parts; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 153)
      Sketches of transcription of Mozart's Symphony in C minor on back.
    - [Trios, violin, cornet, piano], 3 parts; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 153)
    - [Trios (Sketches)], 4 p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 153)
    - [Waltz], 1 score ([3] p.) - 4 parts; 27 x 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 154)
  - Songs, I.E
    - [Absence], 1 score ([1] sheet); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 155)
      See also: Group of songs.
    - [Arrow and the song], 1 score (2 p.); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 155)
      Words by Longfellow.
    - [Arrow and the song (Sketch)], [1] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 155)
    - [As on the sandy beach I lay...], [1] sheet of music; 20 x 27 cm. (Box 12, Folder 156)
      Sketch ([1] sheet; 5 x 27 cm.) laid in.
    - [A bee did see a holly hock... (Sketch)], [2] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 157)
    - [Bonnie Lesley], 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 157)
    - [Bonnie Peg], 1 score ([1] p.); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 157)
      Words by Robert Burns.
    - Bunny
      See: I. Miscellaneous Works. School Song books.
    - [Celtic studies] Four songs published separately: Newton Center, Mass.: Wa-Wan Press, c1905, 1909., 7 scores (5, 5, 5, 6, 4, 6, 7 p.); 31-35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 158)
      Two copies of I-II, IV, and numbers II and IV contain markings.
      Contents: I. Poem by John Todhunter (soprano) - II. Poem by Fiona Macleod (medium voice) - III. Poem by Nora Chesson (medium voice) - IV. Poem by a Viking Skald (baritone or tenor robusto).
    - [Celtic studies. III (Sketches)], [1] sheet of music; 27 x 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 158)
    - [Celtic studies; arr. (Sketch)], 1 score (11 p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 158)
      Incomplete, lacking last pages of no. II on, and words.
    - [Christmas has come. Text], [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 12, Folder 159)
      Typescript with pencil sketch and note.
      "E.S. Brooks, St. Nicholas, November 1882" - at end.
      "Song del'vd in Jan. 1922."
    - [Clinkum Clankum], 1 score ([1] sheet); 36 cm. (Box 12, Folder 159)
      Words by John Ludlow.
      "Copyright 1904/1905 by Ginn & Co."
      "Rocking chair songs" - folder.
      "No. 9."
      See also: I. Miscellaneous Works. School song books.
    - Coasting
      See: I. Miscellaneous Works. School song books.
    - [Cold lunch], 1 score ([1] p.); 36 cm. (Box 12, Folder 161)
      Holograph in ink with pencil markings.
      "Rocking chair song material" - folder.
    - [Cold weather], 1 score ([3] p.) 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 161)
      Found in envelope labeled "School songs."
    - [Cool are the smiling lips of night], 1 score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 162)
      Holograph signed, in ink with text pasted on.
      Words by George Turner Phelps.
    - [Croon of the dew]
      - [Croon of the dew], 1 score (7 p.); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 163)
        Two copies, one each for high and low voice.
      - [Croon of the dew], 1 score (pp. 95-98), bound; 32 cm. (Box 12, Folder 164)
        In: Songs by thirty Americans, edited by Rupert Hughes.
    - [Curl] (Box 12, Folder 165)
      See also: F. Voice and Instrumental Ensemble. Curl; arr.
      - [Curl], 1 score (3 p.); 35 cm.
        Words by Amelis Rives.
        Op. 2/3.
        "Scotch song" - cover.
      - [Curl], 1 score (3 p.); 31 cm.
    - [Day is down into his bow'r...], 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 166)
      Words by Owen Meredith.
      Dated: 1893 Jul 29.
    - [Dollykins] (Box 12, Folder 167)
      - [Dollykins], 1 score ([1] p.); 36 cm.
        Words and music by Henry Gilbert.
        "Copyright 1915 by the Rocking Chair Syndicate."
        Sketch crossed out on back.
      - [Dollykins], 1 score ([1] sheet); 31 cm.
        Two copies, 1 with note by Henry Gilbert.
        Three proof sheets for the above published score; 17 x 22, and 22 x 28 cm.
        From "Rocking Chair Songs."
    - [Dollykins. Text], [1] sheet; 28 cm. (Box 12, Folder 167)
      "Copyright 1915, by the Rocking Chair Syndicate."
    - [Done caught a rabbit (Sketch)], [1] sheet of music; 24 cm. (Box 12, Folder 168)
      Holograph in ink with pencil notes.
    - [Don't be afraid of the dark Nell] Don't be afraid of the dark Nell / music by Frank Belknap [pseudonym]., 1 score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 169)
      First and last pages are glued together.
    - [Down the harbor], 1 score ([1] p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 170)
      "Rocking Chair material" - folder.
      "N.9" - p. [1].
    - [Faery song] (Box 12, Folder 171)
      - [Faery song], 1 score ([3] p.); 20-34 cm.
      - [Faery song], 1 score (4 p.); 36 cm.
        Words by W.B. Yeats from "The Land of Heart's Desire."
        Two copies, one marked "Last copy."
        Also included are a cover and 2 p. introduction by Farwell with corrections in ink by Henry Gilbert?
    - [Faery song (Sketch)], [1] p. of music; 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 171)
    - [Fair Helen] Boston: Bruce Humphries, no date., 1 score ([2] p.); 31 cm. (Box 12, Folder 172)
      Op. 1, no. 2.
      See also: Group of songs; and F. Voice and Instrumental. Fair Helen; arr.
    - [Fichtenbaum steht einsam], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 173)
      English translation of words by Heine in ink before but not in the score.
      Dated: 1891 May 13.
    - [Fichtenbaum steht einsam (Sketch)], [4] p. of music; 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 173)
    - [Fish wharf rhapsody] (Box 12, Folder 174)
      - [Fish wharf rhapsody], 1 score ([8] p.); 35 cm.
        Words by "Fritz" (Frederick Manley) [G.W. Beauchamp].
        "Left over from an afternoon's loaf on Fish Wharf - Boston" - p. 1.
      - [Fish wharf rhapsody], 1 score (8 p.); 34 cm.
      - [Fish wharf rhapsody], 1 score (7 p.); 34 cm.
        Pick-up to first measure crossed out.
      - Fish wharf rhapsody / [words by] "Will" (George William Beauchamp) [music by] "Hank" (Henry F. Gilbert). - Newton Center, Mass. Wa-Wan Press, c1909., 1 score (9 p.); 35 cm.
      - [Fish wharf rhapsody], Proof sheets for the above published score; 32 cm.
        Contains corrections in ink and pencil by Henry Gilbert.
        "Fritz" (Frederick Manley) is crossed out and "Tom" (Thomas Tweed) is added.
    - [From Joyce's Chamber music (Sketches)], 1 score ([4] p.); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 175)
      Holograph (?) in ink.
      "To Laura Williams if she can stand it" - p. [1].
    - [Funny fact] (Box 12, Folder 176)
      - [Funny fact], 1 score ([2] p.); 36 cm.
        "Copyright 1915 by the Rocking Chair Syndicate" - p. [1].
      - [Funny fact], [1] sheet of music; 32 cm.
        Three copies, one with markings by Henry Gilbert also labeled "No. 2" (Rocking Chair Songs), another cut and pasted to be used as proof sheets.
    - [Give me the splendid silent sun] (Box 12, Folder 177)
      - [Give me the splendid silent sun], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
        Words by Walt Whitman.
        "Engrave Royal Quarto" - note on cover.
      - [Give me the splendid silent sun], 1 score ([3] p.); 31 cm.
      - [Give me the splendid silent sun], 1 score (3 p.); 31 cm.
        Two copies, one inscribed by Helen K. Gilbert.
    - [God bless our native land], 1 score ([21 p.); 35 cm. (Box 12, Folder 178)
      Words by C.T. Brooks (1834).
    - [God bless our native land (Sketches)], Loose sheets ([4] p.); 22-34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 178)
    - Good Night
    - [Grasshopper green] (Box 12, Folder 179)
      - [Grasshopper green], 1 score ([2] p.); 34 cm.
        Words by George Cooper.
        "Copyright 1904/1906 by Ginn & Co." - p. [1].
        "No. 3" - p. [1] ("Rocking Chair Songs").
      - [Grasshopper green], 1 score ([2] p.); 36 cm.
        "Copyright 1904/1906 by Ginn & Co. used by permission" - p. [1].
    - [Group of songs] Boston: H.B. Stevens Company, c1894., 8 scores (19 p.); 29 cm. (Box 12, Folder 179)
      Contain special markings.
      Op. 1.
      Contents: No. 1. Absence - No. 2. Fair Helen - No. 3 Happy little flower of May / words by Miss H.J. Wescott - No. 4 Bonnie Lesley / words by Robert Burns - No.5 In the night / words by Jean Ingelow - No. 6 Reverie / words by Oven Meredith - No. 7 Folk song / words from "The boy's magic horn" - No. 8 O saw ye the lass / words by Richard Ryan.
      "First published work 1894" - note on folder.
      See also: Absence; Bonnie Lesley; and Fair Helen.
    - [He takes so long to say good night], 1 score ([4] p.); 34 cm. (Box 12, Folder 180)
      Music by Frank Belknap [pseudonym].
      "Lyrics by Karl Tausig. Copyright: by Karl Tausig 1908" - p. [1] in ink.
    - [Here's hoping. Text], [1] p.; 28 cm. (Box 13, Folder 237)
      Typescript with pencil markings.
      With: That dreamgirl of mine. Text.
    - [Homesick] Boston: Boston Music Company, c1919, 1 score (5 p.); 31 cm. (Box 12, Folder 181)
      Words by Howard Weedon.
    - [I can't catch cold when you're around] (Box 12, Folder 182)
      - [I can't catch cold when you're around], 1 score (III p.); 34 cm.
        Holograph signed, in ink with pencil note.
        Words by Karl Tausig.
        "Copyright 1908 by Karl Tausig" - in ink on p. I.
        Page II-III are glued together.
      - [I can't catch cold when you're around], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
      - [I can't catch cold when you're around], 1 score ([3] p.); 35 cm.
      - [I can't catch cold when you're around], 1 score ([3] p.); 34 cm.
        "Oh you kiddo Waltz" - front cover.
    - [I doan want you hangin' round] (Box 12, Folder 183)